

LORENZO RIGATO

WEB, ANDROID & IOS

DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

A 28 years old mobile and web **developer** with 5+ years of experience.

Strong knowledge on **Android** framework. Clean and **well-structured** code lover. Simple and clear **UI** amazed.

I'm also a motorbike **explorer**, a Stelvio Pass **climber**, a sunset **searcher**, an acoustic guitar **strummer** and a friends tasting pizza **lover**.

CONTACT



llollox.github.com



lore91tanz@gmail.com



+39 333 8600532



Via Sant'Angelo 28/A, Treviso

PERSONAL SKILLS

MOTIVATION

QUICK LEARNER

TEAMWORK

PROBLEM SOLVING



WORK EXPERIENCE

ANDROID & IOS DEVELOPER

Previnet SPA - Treviso, Italy

Nov 2016 to Current (2 years and 8 months)

- Development of the application XME Salute for Intesa Sanpaolo bank on Android platform.
- Design app architecture: separating each component with interfaces, following MVP / MVVM / VIPER patterns and using Dagger 2 and Android Architecture components.
- ❖ Implementation Accessibility on both Android & iOS platforms.

REACT JS DEVELOPER (freelance)

Foodracers srl - Treviso, Italy

Ago 2017 to Sep 2018 (1 year)

- Development of a design system using Storybook and following the CSS BEM methodology.
- ❖ Usage of the **Redux** pattern to structure the code.
- Usage of Turbolinks Android & iOS to embed the react components into a native application.

WEB DEVELOPER

REPLY SPA - Milan, Italy

Apr 2016 to Oct 2016 (6 months)

 Development of DirectLine's responsive web portal using Bootstrap, jQuery and Liferay.

ANDROID DEVELOPER

BELKA SRL - Trento, Italy

Sep 2015 to Mar 2016 (6 months)

- Design and development of Android applications following Material Design rules.
- ❖ Implementation of UI tests using Robolectric.
- Usage of Jira and Kanban board to organize tasks.

RUBY ON RAILS AND ANDROID DEVELOPER

FONDAZIONE BRUNO KESSLER – Trento, Italy

Dec 2011 to Sep 2015 (3 years and 10 months)

- Design and development of Android applications.
- ❖ Implementation of versioned **REST API** on Ruby on Rails.
- Frontend implementation for BringTheFood using Bootstrap.
- Writing code documentation for both API and project structure.
- Usage of git as version control tool.



EDUCATION

COMPUTER SCIENCE MASTER DEGREE

UNIVERSITY OF TRENTO
110 CUM LAUDE / 110

December 2015

COMPUTER SCIENCE BACHELOR DEGREE

UNIVERSITY OF TRENTO

103 / 110

September 2013



iOS

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

ANDROID

RUBY ON RAILS

REACT JS & REDUX

UNIT & UI TESTS

USER INTERACTION & UX